<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filizzi Family</title>
    <link>https://www.filizzi.family/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Filizzi Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 08:55:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.filizzi.family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hip</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20240430-hip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 08:55:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20240430-hip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hip-update&#34;&gt;Hip Update&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I had a procedure scheduled for last Monday.  What was the procedure I hear nobody asking.  Well it was exactly the one that the Oncologist thought I would need, sclerotherapy.  The only difference from what was originally thought was that the issue wasn&amp;rsquo;t an &lt;strong&gt;intramuscular hemangioma&lt;/strong&gt;, it was a vascular malformation that causes blood to pool and cause me pain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-now&#34;&gt;So what now&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well now that the procedure has been done, I am in recovery.  Per the doctor, it should take about two weeks to recover, which is where I am now.  The pain level has been growing for the past week but based on the way I am feeling as I write this I would venture a guess that it has peaked and maybe started to decline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hip Biopsy</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20231215-hip_biopsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 10:37:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20231215-hip_biopsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-hip-saga&#34;&gt;More Hip saga&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything in a long time about my hip story so it&amp;rsquo;s time to document some more.  Since the last post the doctors did a needle biopsy of the hip and everything came back as normal blood and muscle.  This was in line with the belief that my hip issue is caused by an Intramuscular Hemangioma.  After that they preformed an Angiogram with the intent to close the blood vessels that are feeding it (the Sclerotherapy from the last post).  However when they preformed that, it was determinied that it is not a hemangioma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continued Hip Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230530-continuedhipsaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 09:41:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230530-continuedhipsaga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-another-hip-update&#34;&gt;So another hip update&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one happened about a week ago, I just haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to posting it.  Last week I had an appointment with an Orthopedic Oncologist.  It is a good news/bad news situation.  Good news is that it is something she has seen before, an Intramuscular Hemangioma.  Which isn&amp;rsquo;t cancerous.  The bad news is treatment isn&amp;rsquo;t all that successful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what is treatment?  Well it&amp;rsquo;s something called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.upmc.com/services/south-central-pa/heart-vascular/vascular/vein-center/treatments-services/sclerotherapy?utm_mrid=mrid2319&amp;amp;utm_source=GOOGLE&amp;amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_campaign=71700000083218625&amp;amp;utm_adgroup=58700007070499999&amp;amp;utm_term=sclerotherapy&amp;amp;utm_advertiserid=700000002154619&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&#34;&gt;Sclerotherapy&lt;/a&gt;.  If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve it we can do surgery to remove the mass however because it is so ill defined there is no guarantee that it&amp;rsquo;ll all be removed and not come back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Hip</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230511-more_hip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 12:22:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230511-more_hip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;another-hip-update&#34;&gt;Another Hip Update&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I ended up having another MRI on my hip a week ago.  This time with contrast.  What they saw was a mass in my hip about 4 inches by 2.5 inches by almost an inch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notes from the MRI where vaguely worded and gave both myself and my wife a panic, but after talking with the orthopedist it seems less to be worried about (most likely not cancer, and no concern of deteriorating ball joints).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hip Issue</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230425-hip_followup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 09:01:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230425-hip_followup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-have-a-hip-problem&#34;&gt;I have a Hip Problem&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok so That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a vague statement.  Really I&amp;rsquo;ve had a hip problem when I was a child.  When I was 8, I believe, my parents saw me limping around and took me to the doctor.  They did X-Rays and found calcium deposits in my left hip.  Other than the X-Rays every year or so they did nothing.  By age 12 they were gone.  Over the years my hip has always been an issue, if I sit too much or on an uncomfortable seat my hip will scream at me.  I&amp;rsquo;ve done Physical Therapy numerous times with no real relief&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Update</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230327-project_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:21:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230327-project_update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago I decided I wanted a mechanical keyboard.  Specifically I wanted a proper ergonomic keyboard.  So I did a bunch of research on various types/models.  I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid of soldering so I could do one completely by hand if I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a LOT of mechanical keyboard options out there, but once you start looking at ergonomic ones, the options shrink.  Most of what I had found were &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keychron.com/products/keychron-q8-alice-layout-qmk-custom-mechanical-keyboard&#34;&gt;Alice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.diykeyboards.com/keyboards/keyboard-kits/product/dactyl-manuform-kit&#34;&gt;Dactyl&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; based ones.  I wanted something a bit more normal than a Dactyl and a bit more ergonomic than an Alice.  I ended up deciding on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mechwild.com/product/mokulua/&#34;&gt;Mechwild Mokulua&lt;/a&gt;.  Except for a soldering issue that I managed to lift a few circuits off of the right half of the board it really was easy to build.  I did have to customize the key layout a bit because they didn&amp;rsquo;t prioritize some keys tha I use regularly, but that was easy enough to do and all my changes are publicly &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/mfilizzi/qmk_firmware&#34;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; if anyone wanted it.  I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it to anyone who wants to make one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditation</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230125-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:33:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20230125-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;meditation&#34;&gt;Meditation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am an avid meditator.  I first started about 15 years ago when I was attending&#xA;the local UU church.  Initially it was very infrequent, maybe once a month.  I&#xA;eventually started attending &lt;a href=&#34;http://bmls.org&#34;&gt;Blue Mountin Lotus Society&lt;/a&gt;, at&#xA;first every other week.  Sarah could tell the difference in my personality when&#xA;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then Covid happened.  Everywhere shut down.  I was unable to continue going to&#xA;my regular weekly meditations.  I tried do do it by muself at home, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;anywhere near consistant.  I tried to find online meditations but was having&#xA;trouble finding anything that I liked.  I was starting to be in a real bad way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krypto</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220916-krypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 10:52:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220916-krypto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;krypto&#34;&gt;Krypto&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has been with me through thick and thin.  My ex and I got him when he was somewhere between 8 and 10 weeks old.  That was over 12 years ago.  He was there for me when we got divorced.  He was there for me on those nights when I came home to an otherwise empty house.  He was there for me when I started dating again and when I got married to my wonderful wife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dad Updated</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220303-dad_updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:58:34 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220303-dad_updated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;updates-on-my-dad&#34;&gt;Updates on my dad&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On March 1st my dad was transferred to rehab to help him get back some of his mobility and functionality.  While I never got confirmation, we all assumed that they had his blood pressure under control and that his kidneys were starting to function better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two days later I received a call from my brother, which was my first red flag since he never calls.  I should note that the call was before 9am, which was my second red flag.  He was calling to tell me the bad news, he had just spoken to the rehab place and apparently dad had passed away over night, presumably in his sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dad</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220222-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 10:59:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220222-dad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fall&#34;&gt;Fall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday February 22nd I received a call from my brother.  This is unusual for a number of reasons, the first being that neither he nor my father ever call me.  It always ends up being on me to call them to find out what is going on in their lives and update them on everything around here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was calling to let me know that our dad had fallen &amp;ldquo;a couple of days ago&amp;rdquo;, and that he was still hurting and having a hard time moving around.  Apparently it had gotten to the point where my brother decided it was time to force something to happen.  An ambulance ended up coming to the house and took dad to the ER. My father was admitted with a cracked rib, high blood pressure and his kidneys are not working optimally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where did all the stars go</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211129-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:59:34 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211129-stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-did-all-the-stars-go&#34;&gt;Where did all the stars go?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was young I loved looking up at the stars to try to spot constilations.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at it but I could usually find the Big Bipper and Orion, season permitting, among all the other points of light in the sky.  In college I knew people who would go lay out in the field nearby to watch the meteor showers.  It was something magical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mom</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211007-mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 19:01:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211007-mom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mom&#34;&gt;Mom&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today would have been my mom&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I believe her 67th one, but I am not sure about that.  She passed away twelve years ago next month.  Sometimes I still think about her and miss her but it has been a long time and a lot has happened.  I am sure that my youngest son has no memory of her, and my oldest would have been 4 when she passed so I don&amp;rsquo;t think he remembers her either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Family stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210622-morefamily/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 15:19:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210622-morefamily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dna-test&#34;&gt;DNA Test&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had previously mentioned that my wife bought me DNA test for my birthday.  While I had to wait a while to get the results, I have them now and have actually had them for about a month.  This gave me some time to think about my results a bit before posting anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.filizzi.family/images/20210622-MoreFamily/Region.png&#34; alt=&#34;DNA Result Map&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results are not quite what I expected.  While I knew a majority of my ancestry came from Germany, hard to be from central PA and that not be the case, I did not expect that Italian would be so low down the list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210418-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 07:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210418-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;family&#34;&gt;Family&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about family for the last few weeks.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because my wife gave me a DNA test for my birthday and I&amp;rsquo;m waiting on the results.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve never been close with my extended family due to falling outs my parents had when my brother and I were young.  Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because my oldest son just turned 16.  Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s becaus COVID has kept me sepearted from almost everyone I consider family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pets</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210216-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210216-pets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks, and over the next few weeks a lot of changes have happened (and will happen) to the animals in our home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting with the sad news, our older cat &lt;strong&gt;Maisy&lt;/strong&gt; starting having litter box issues.  After taking her to the vet we discovered advanced kidney disease.  The vet first perscribed a medicine for that along with special food.  This helped however she started vomitting all over the place, almost more than she was eating.  They then perscribed two other medicines to help, however they caused her to stop eating all together.  In addition to all this, while she was never a large cat, her weight has dropped into alarming teritory.  They think in addition to kidney disease she also has some sort of bowel cancer.  We were trying to just make her comfortable until we say our final good byes next week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts About the Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210214-linuxdesktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 10:06:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210214-linuxdesktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;linux-desktops&#34;&gt;Linux Desktops&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have used a wide variety of Linux desktops.  Some for a (very) short period of time, others for years at a time.  I&amp;rsquo;ve come to classify them into two categories.  The first one would be ones that replicate the user experience of another operating system such as Microsoft Windows or Mac OS.  The other classification would be ones that are willing to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects I&#39;m playing with</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20201214-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 11:36:54 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20201214-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;m going to detail out what I&amp;rsquo;m playing with these days.  Not just technology but things in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;programming&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m re-teaching myself Ruby.  But not for Rails.  I find the language very elegant, and wish I had kept up to date with the development of the language but life happens.  Now I&amp;rsquo;m back to a place where I feel comfortable re-teaching myself some of the programming languages that I used to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Me</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/about/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:53:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/about/me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a computer programmer by training who is currently working as a project manager for a range of small to large applications, most of which are web based.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am also a gaming enthusist.  Most peole hear that and think video games, and while I do enjoy some video games I am more interested in tabletop games.  In addition to just playing them I also volunteer my time with an organization who promotes the use of tabletop gaming for educational and theraputic purposes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebodhanagroup.org/&#34;&gt;The Bodhana Group&lt;/a&gt;.  Personally gaming has helped me to overcome my social anxiety.  I met my wife because of tabletop gaming, and it has been a way to bond with my children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filizzi Family</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/about/family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 11:09:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/about/family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Filizzi Family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Filizzi is a mis-spelled last name from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tollo&#34;&gt;Tollo region of Italy&lt;/a&gt;.  The best I can tell is that when my Great-Great Grandfather came to the US his last name was mis-spelled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I do more genology research I will update this page with more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
