<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Filizzi Family</title>
    <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Filizzi Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 10:59:11 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.filizzi.family/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dad</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220222-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 10:59:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20220222-dad/</guid>
      <description>Fall On Tuesday February 22nd I received a call from my brother. This is unusual for a number of reasons, the first being that neither he nor my father ever call me. It always ends up being on me to call them to find out what is going on in their lives and update them on everything around here.
He was calling to let me know that our dad had fallen &amp;ldquo;a couple of days ago&amp;rdquo;, and that he was still hurting and having a hard time moving around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where did all the stars go</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211129-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:59:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211129-stars/</guid>
      <description>Where did all the stars go? When I was young I loved looking up at the stars to try to spot constilations. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at it but I could usually find the Big Bipper and Orion, season permitting, among all the other points of light in the sky. In college I knew people who would go lay out in the field nearby to watch the meteor showers. It was something magical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mom</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211007-mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 19:01:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20211007-mom/</guid>
      <description>Mom Today would have been my mom&amp;rsquo;s birthday, I believe her 67th one, but I am not sure about that. She passed away twelve years ago next month. Sometimes I still think about her and miss her but it has been a long time and a lot has happened. I am sure that my youngest son has no memory of her, and my oldest would have been 4 when she passed so I don&amp;rsquo;t think he remembers her either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Family stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210622-morefamily/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 15:19:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210622-morefamily/</guid>
      <description>DNA Test I had previously mentioned that my wife bought me DNA test for my birthday. While I had to wait a while to get the results, I have them now and have actually had them for about a month. This gave me some time to think about my results a bit before posting anything.
The results are not quite what I expected. While I knew a majority of my ancestry came from Germany, hard to be from central PA and that not be the case, I did not expect that Italian would be so low down the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210418-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 07:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210418-family/</guid>
      <description>Family So I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about family for the last few weeks. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because my wife gave me a DNA test for my birthday and I&amp;rsquo;m waiting on the results. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve never been close with my extended family due to falling outs my parents had when my brother and I were young. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because my oldest son just turned 16. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s becaus COVID has kept me sepearted from almost everyone I consider family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pets</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210216-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210216-pets/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks, and over the next few weeks a lot of changes have happened (and will happen) to the animals in our home.
Starting with the sad news, our older cat Maisy starting having litter box issues. After taking her to the vet we discovered advanced kidney disease. The vet first perscribed a medicine for that along with special food. This helped however she started vomitting all over the place, almost more than she was eating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts About the Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210214-linuxdesktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 10:06:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20210214-linuxdesktop/</guid>
      <description>Linux Desktops Over the years I have used a wide variety of Linux desktops. Some for a (very) short period of time, others for years at a time. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to classify them into two categories. The first one would be ones that replicate the user experience of another operating system such as Microsoft Windows or Mac OS. The other classification would be ones that are willing to try something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects I&#39;m playing with</title>
      <link>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20201214_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 11:36:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.filizzi.family/posts/20201214_projects/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;m going to detail out what I&amp;rsquo;m playing with these days. Not just technology but things in general.
Programming Ruby I&amp;rsquo;m re-teaching myself Ruby. But not for Rails. I find the language very elegant, and wish I had kept up to date with the development of the language but life happens. Now I&amp;rsquo;m back to a place where I feel comfortable re-teaching myself some of the programming languages that I used to use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
